comebackmomma.com 2019-03-31

# Privacy Policy | Comeback Momma

By visiting Comeback Momma, you are consenting to our privacy policy.  Comeback Momma (“Company”) is committed to protecting your privacy online.  This Privacy Policy describes the personal information we collect through this website at www.comebackmomma.com (the “Site”),

Visitors and any users of the site are referred to as “user”, “you” and “your” and Company is referred to as “we”, “us”, and “our”.  Accessing this Site constitutes a use of the Site and an acceptance to our Privacy Policy.

On the Site, we provide information about healthy living, parenting, food, fitness, and entertainment.

Use of the Site, including all materials presented herein and all online Services provided by Company, is subject to the following Privacy Policy.  This Privacy Policy applies to all site visitors, customers and all other users of the Site.  By using the Site or Service, you agree to this Privacy Policy, without modification, and acknowledge reading it.

### WHAT PERSONAL DATA WE COLLECT:

  * This Site collects the personal information you voluntarily provide to us, which includes your name and e-mail address, in order to subscribe to our newsletter or comment on our blog.  If you opt-in to receive our newsletter, the option to unsubscribe will be included in every e-mail.
  * If you purchase a product, your payment information will be processed by a trusted third party vendor (Amazon or PayPal, for example).  We do not store this payment information on our site or in our files.
  * This site may also collect aggregate demographic information through Google Analytics, such as gender, age, and preferences/interests.  This analytical data is not personally identified to you in any way.  We use this information to provide you with relevant content and we use aggregated data from Google Analytics to provide demographic info on our site (percentage of male vs female readers; top geographic locations) for sponsored content opportunities.

### WHAT WE DO WITH THE INFORMATION WE GATHER:

  * We may use the information to advertise products or services, or to keep you up to date on recent posts, via our email list.
  * We may use the information to improve our products and services, or gather ideas for content.
  * We may record information relating to your use of the Site in order to help administer the Site and personalize your experience by improving customer service.
  * We may use aggregate demographic information to share with third parties for sponsored content opportunities.

### **COMMENTS:**

When visitors leave comments on the site we collect the data shown in the comments form, and also the visitor’s IP address and browser user agent string to help spam detection.

An anonymized string created from your email address (also called a hash) may be provided to the Gravatar service to see if you are using it. The Gravatar service privacy policy is [available here](https://automattic.com/privacy/).  After approval of your comment, your profile picture is visible to the public in the context of your comment.

### COOKIES:

Additionally, we may send cookies to your computer in order to identify your improve our service.  These are small data files that are stored on your browser, and are used by many categories of websites (including ours).

If you leave a comment on our site you may opt-in to saving your name, email address and website in cookies. These are for your convenience so that you do not have to fill in your details again when you leave another comment.

At any point, you may decline the cookies in your Internet browser settings.  However, doing so may prevent use of some of the Site.

### **EMBEDDED CONTENT FROM OTHER WEBSITES:**

Articles on this site may include embedded content (e.g. videos, images, articles, etc.). Embedded content from other websites behaves in the exact same way as if the visitor has visited the other website.

These websites may collect data about you, use cookies, embed additional third-party tracking, and monitor your interaction with that embedded content, including tracing your interaction with the embedded content if you have an account and are logged in to that website.

### THIRD PARTIES:

We do not sell your information to third parties.

We do use third parties to assist with some of the functions in this site, and as such your data may be shared with those and/or cookies may be used with those.  These currently include the following:

  * Google Analytics – We use google analytics to provide us with information about site volume, site navigation, user sessions, and demographic data.  We may also use Google Analytics to track clicks to a particular link within a page.
  * Mailchimp – We use Mailchimp for the email newsletter form, to store email addresses, and to send out a weekly email newsletter.
  * Share-A-Sale – We use Share-A-Sale for affiliate marketing purposes, including links in posts and advertisements on the sidebar, which includes a tracking cookie to assess purchases.
  * Amazon – We use Amazon for affiliate marketing purposes, which includes a tracking cookie to assess purchases.
  * Awin – We use Awin for affiliate marketing purposes, which includes a tracking cookie to assess purchases.

Each third-party service provider has their own privacy policy and their use of your information is dictated by such.  All of the above are considered reliable companies and none should be using your data inappropriately.  To the best of our knowledge, they are all following GDPR best practices.

This list may be updated from time to time Website’s sole discretion.

This Site may also contain links to third party websites.  Unless otherwise stated, this Privacy Policy only covers information that we collect from you on this Site. Any other link will be covered by the privacy policy of that specific site.  You acknowledge and accept that we are not responsible for the privacy policies or practices of third parties.

We sometimes use Bitly to create specific trackable links.  In this case, the only data we have access to is the number of times a link was clicked.

### **HOW LONG WE RETAIN YOUR DATA:**

If you leave a comment, the comment and its metadata are retained indefinitely. This is so we can recognize and approve any follow-up comments automatically instead of holding them in a moderation queue.

If you submit an email address to sign up for our email newsletter, this will also be retained indefinitely, or until either you unsubscribe or we decide to discontinue our email newsletter.

### ADVERTISING & AFFILIATES

Display Ads:  This website provides display ads via our affiliate marketing partnerships through Amazon, Share-a-Sale, or Awin.

Affiliate Marketing:  This website uses affiliate links, which are links that provide a commission back to us when you purchase a product.  It tracks these purchases using a cookie.  It does not change the user experience in anyway.

### SECURITY & DATA BREACHES:

We do our best to protect your information for any unauthorized access, misuse, or disclosure.  In the event we discover a data breach, we will notify you within 72 hours.

However, you acknowledge that the personal information you voluntarily share could be accessed or tampered with by a third party.  You agree that we are not responsible for any intercepted information shared through our Site without our knowledge or permission.  Additionally, you release us from any and all claims arising out of or related to the use of such intercepted information in any unauthorized manner.

### CHILDREN – ONLINE PRIVACY PROTECTION ACT COMPLIANCE

To access or use the Site, you must be 18 years old or older and have the requisite power and authority to enter into this Privacy Policy.  We do not knowingly collect or solicit data online from or market online to children under the age of 18.

If a parent or guardian believes that the Website has personally identifiable information of a child under the age of 16 in its database, please contact us immediately so that we may remove such data.

### YOUR RIGHTS RELATED TO THIS INFORMATION

At any time, you have the right to the following:

  * Opt-out – You may opt-out of email communications from us by using the unsubscribe button at the bottom of our email list, or by emailing a request to comebackmomma@gmail.com.  You may also email us directly if you would like access to a “freebie”/lead magnet but do not want to subscribe to the mailing list in order to access it.
  * Understand Your Data – You can email us anytime to better understand the data that we have on file about you.  Please reach out to comebackmomma@gmail.com.
  * Delete/Forget Your Data – You can request that we erase your personal data.  (Please note that there may be legal situations, bookkeeping requirements, or requirements to complete a transaction that require retaining the data for a certain period of time.)  Please reach out to comebackmomma@gmail.com.

### CHANGES TO THIS POLICY

You acknowledge and agree that you have reviewed this Site and this Privacy Policy and that you will continue to review to be aware of any modifications.  Any changes to this Policy will be updated on this page.

### CONTACT:

If at any point you have any questions related to this privacy, please email comebackmomma@gmail.com.

**_Updated:   January 2019_**
